PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(jumping, bouncing)
(light switches on)
- Great work.
干得好
So far we've built up a model of hair
现在我们建了一个头发模型
using a series of damped springs.
通过使用一系列的阻尼弹簧
This gives us a more realistic behavior,
这给我们更真实的效果
like this style I came up with.
就像这样
But remember, the art department
但记住 艺术部门想要merida的头发
wants Merida's hair to be curly.
是卷曲的
Sometimes it curls up while moving but it doesn't
有时候他在运动时是卷的
hold that curly shape while at rest.
但在静止时就不卷了
Here's an idea.
这里有一个方法
What if we put some smaller springs in between
我们何不放一些小弹簧
the larger springs to pull them together?
到大弹簧之间 把他们拉在一起
Let's call them support springs.
我们就叫它们支撑弹簧
We already have a mathematical model of the spring
我们已经有了一个弹簧的数学模型
so this is easy to test out.
所以这个实验起来很简单
If I connect a support spring between the larger
如果我在大弹簧之间连小弹簧
springs, I get something like this.
他看起来就像这样
If I hide the support springs, you'll notice the hair
如果我设小弹簧不可见
comes to a rest in a curly shape.
你就会看到头发在静止时也是卷曲的
That's much better.
这好多了
Adding these support springs results
加上这些小弹簧
in new parameters we can control.
意味着我们能添加更多的控制器
The stiffness and length of the support springs.
就是支撑弹簧的弹性系数和长度
Shorter support springs will give us smaller curls,
小的产生小卷儿
while really long support springs give us bigger ones.
大的能有大波浪
And if we make the support springs have a higher stiffness
如果更硬
the curl pops up like this.
卷曲就像这样弹
Kind of like we applied hairspray.
就像我们用了发胶一样
Compare this to support springs with lower stiffness.
弹性系数小一些
In this case, the curls relax a bit
卷儿就比较蓬松
and fall downwards in a natural way.
自然下垂
Now, let's try this with a bunch of hairs.
然后我们来试试一堆头发的情况
Now that's starting to look more like Merida.
现在更像merida了
This isn't exactly the method we used on Merida
这虽然不是我们真正用在merida身上的方法
for the movie, but it's close.
但很接近了
In this next interactive you can try this out
在下一个交互里 你可以试试这个
with all the parameters we've introduced.
用我们介绍过的这些参数
The two new parameters are support spring stiffness
这两个新的就是支撑弹簧的弹性系数
and support spring length.
和长度
See what you can come up with.
看看你能做出些什么 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox